

SATYABAN BADU

Mobile: 77520 25983.

Email: - satyaban.badu81@gmail.com

Over 20 yrs. of experience in the Information Technology Industry and a good exposure in designing of LAN, WAN & establishing Server Client relationship. Team players with good interpersonal skills, established and maintained productive communication with all levels of management & fellow employees.

Skill Summary:

| Operating Systems | Microsoft: Windows 2000/2003/2008, NT 4.0 Servers & Workstation, Windows XP, |
|-------------------|---|
| | Windows -7 & Windows-10. |
| Server | Compaq Proliant Server 1600, ML 300 series. HP Proliant Server of ML & DL |
| | Series, IBM X Series 225 servers & DELL Power Edge2900. |
| Desktop | Compaq & HP Desktops, Wipro desktops, DELL & IBM PC-AT Compatible Assemble PCs. |
| Networking Skills | □ LAN and Intranet Designing. |
| _ | ☼ Maintaining and trouble shooting of Local Area Network. |
| | ▽ Establishing Network Connectivity using Lease Line, Routers, V.35 & G.703 modems. |
| | ☼ Designing & commissioning the new branch from IT-Prospective |
| | → Well Versed in TCP/IP environment. |

System Integration & Software Solution Skills: -

- Configuring & maintaining various type of Intel Product with different type of Microsoft O. S, Red Hat Linux.
- Configuration of Hardware RAID with Smart Array 530/5i ultra 3 wide SCSI Controller for MS Windows NT/2000/2003 Server.

Academic Credential

- → B. Sc
- □ ITIL, MCSE, MCP, MCDBA, Advance Diploma in Hardware & Networking from IIHT.

Employment History

- Presently working for Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd (Earlier named as Magma Fincorp Ltd) from March 2008 to till as Zonal IT-Manager & taking care of EAST & Central Zone (C.G, M.P, Odisha & Jharkhand & Bihar), now posted At Bhubaneswar. Handling both Infrastructure & Operation.
- As Assistant System Engineer at TCS (On behalf of Maples) from October 2006 to March 2008.
- As Customer Support Engineer at CMS Computers Ltd. from December 2003 to October2006.

Training: -

- ¬ Attended Training Program for Microsoft Windows 2003 server at Magma Fincorp Limited Kolkata.
- Tattended Training Program for Designing, Implementing & Commissioning of new Branches from IT-Prospective at Magma Fincorp Limited Kolkata.
- Attended Training Program for ITIL at Tatasky Ltd Kolkata arranged by TCS.

Highlights

<u>Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd (Earlier named as Magma Fincorp Limited) as a Zonal IT-Manager (Mar-2008 to till date)</u>

- 1. Within a short time, frame (7month) I have successfully commissioned 19branches from IT-Prospective across all over India.
- 2. Implemented Lotus Notes (Client-8) across West Zone, with the help of CMS Team.
- **3.** Migration of Lotus Client to O365.

Responsibility: -

- 1. As per the IT-Policy defined by the Management (CIO) of the Magma Fincorp Ltd, I plan & maintain the Server Room layout of a new branch, where the AC, Server Equipments & Server will be placed from the Safety & security consideration.
- 2. Sustain the N/W cabling structure.
- 3. Sustain the Electrical Consideration.
- 4. Sustain the Earthing Consideration
- 5. Sustain the Environmental Consideration.
- **6.** Coordinate with N/W cabling Vendor, UPS Vendor, VSNL/Tulip & BSNL people to provide the Main link (RF) & backup as ISDN link

Assigned with few more Responsibility: -

- Implementing & Maintaining Windows-2003, 2008, 2012 Server across West Zone (22nos DELL-PoweEdge-2900 Server). Configure DHCP, DNS, ADS, Group Policy, WSUS & AV (Trend Micro)
- Act as a single point of contact for interacting with respective vendors and resolving the problems. Vendor like: -HP, IBM, DELL, Power ware, Emerson & CMS
- Maintain the update Inventory sheet & IT-Deployment of West Region
- · Assign PC & Mail-Id to a new user, as per the policy defined by the Management
- Take the reporting & call report from CMS RE (8nos) on daily basis across the East Zone
- Consolidating East Zone Backup Reports of Windows-2003/2008 Server on Daily Basis
- Resolving the remote location call by taking Net Meeting or Remote Desktop, if Engineer is fall short to give the Solution at the Remote site.
- Implementing & Execution of PSD (Poonawalla Service Desk). It is a call logging tool.

<u>Tata Consultancy Ltd (TCS—On behalf of Maples). Tatasky Ltd as Asst System Engineer (Oct-2006 to Mar-2008)</u>

Achievements at Tatasky Ltd. Project: -

After 8 Months of joining, I was elected as technical team leader for East Zone.

Providing technical Solutions to all engineers located at East Zone.

After 4 months I was elected under L2 NOC team Tatasky for Monitoring Switch & Router for East Zone.

Assigned With few more Responsibilities: -

- 1) Consolidating East Zone Daily Call Reports & Sending it to All India Team Leader Tatasky on Daily Basis.
- 2) Consolidating East Zone Daily Check Least & Sending It to All India Team Leader Tatasky on Weekly Basis.
- 3) Consolidating East Zone ADS Server Check Least & Sending It to All India Team Leader Tatasky on Daily Basis.
- 4) Vendor Management, Asset Management, Backup Calls, Mail Management, Anti-Virus Support: Cabling, Patch Panel and EPABX Support are the additional responsibilities in Tata Sky Ltd.

CMS Computers Ltd. (Dec-2003 to Oct-2006) as Customer Support Engineer (FMS)

- HDFC STANDARD LIFE INSURANCE: As a Residence Engineer managing the IT infrastructure, maintaining Windows NT sever, and Lotus domino clients for users was my responsibility.
- ❖ CitiFinancial Bhubaneswar: Maintaining the IT infrastructure, vendor co-ordination, allocating the IT resources for optimal endeavor, was my prime responsibility, as a system administrator.
- Magma Leasing Limited

Responsibility: -

- ☑ IT Helpdesk Engineer for Orissa, Mail Management. (Outlook & Ms-Outlook 2000/03)
- ☑ Call Management, User Management, IT Asset Management.
- ☑ System Management, Server Management, Network Management.
- ☑ Software & Applications Maintenance, Logistic Management.
- ☑ Vendor Management, Switch, Hub, Router, LAN infrastructure management.

As the IT Administrator, infrastructure planning, maintaining, managing the user's day to day problems, assigning proper rights to use the resources, securing the data and intranetworking, regularly checking the intranet link for smother operation is my key job responsibility.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Name Satyaban Badu

Permanent Address $\ \ \,$ Satyaban Badu

At/Po – Swastik Niwas, Near Boitalu Temple Plot No-1982/1985, Old Town, Bhubaneswar,

Orissa, Pin-751002.

Present Address Same as Above

Language Known Oriya, Hindi & English

(Satyaban Badu)